(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
暁光を繋いで
Connecting the dawn light
この先へ僕ら
As we move forward
公式チャンネルにてMV公開中！！！
暁光クロニクル GYOKOU CHRONICLE
MV now available on the official channel!!!
Gyokou Chronicle
秘密結社holoX 3周年
『暁光クロニクル』リリース記念ボイス
Secret Society holoX 3rd Anniversary
'Gyokou Chronicle' Release Celebration Voice Packs
秘密結社holoX 3周年記念！
公式メンバーシップ限定壁紙・限定絵文字
Secret Society holoX 3rd Anniversary Celebration!
Official Membership Exclusive Wallpapers and Emotes
踏み出した一歩が
The first step we took
道になる
Will become our path
暁光を繋いで
Connecting the dawn light
この先へ僕ら
As we move forward
踏み出した一歩が
The first step we took
道になる
Will become our path
暁光を繋いで
Connecting the dawn light
この先へ僕ら
As we move forward
踏み出した一歩が
The first step we took
道になる
Will become our path
公式チャンネルにてMV公開中！！！
暁光クロニクル GYOUKOU CHRONICLE
Music video now available on the official channel!!!
Gyoukou Chronicle
秘密結社holoX 3周年
『暁光クロニクル』リリース記念ボイス
Secret Society holoX 3rd Anniversary
'Gyoukou Chronicle' Release Commemoration Voice
秘密結社holoX 3周年記念！
公式メンバーシップ 限定壁紙・限定絵文字
Secret Society holoX 3rd Anniversary!
Official Membership Limited Wallpapers & Emotes
ある日、突如として現れた謎の組織"holoX"
One day, a mysterious organization "holoX" suddenly appeared.
構成員5名。与えられたミッションを達成すべく、今、立ち上がる！
Five members. To achieve their given mission, they rise up now!
ちょーゆめドデッカイ！
Super dream huge!
ぜったいぜったい
Definitely, definitely
どこまでもドデッカイ
Huge everywhere
でっかいさあ行こう！
Huge, let's go!
Oh Yeah!
本日のアジェンダです
Today's agenda is...
(なになに〜？)
(What is it?)
KPIにコミットするファクトをオーソライズすること
To authorize facts that commit to the KPI
(なにそれ！？)
(What's that!?)
ふぁ〜 徹夜明けグロッキーです
Yawn... I'm groggy after an all-nighter.
(ふっか〜っ！)
(Deep breath!)
これじゃ喋る術無いようなもんですねぇ
At this rate, there's no way to talk.
(はぁ〜)
(Sigh...)
日本中を駆け回って (おー！)
Running all around Japan (Oh!)
困難ミッション遂行 せねば回らないらしい
It seems it won't work unless we complete the difficult mission.
ちょっとだけ不安です それでも
I'm a bit anxious. Even so...
我らやるしかない！ 皆の者、かかれ！
We have no choice but to do it! Everyone, charge!
Yes My Dark!
ちょーゆめドデッカイ！ ぜったいぜったい
Super dream huge! Definitely, definitely
手合わせてドデッカイ！ でっかいせーので
Clasping hands, huge! Huge, one-two-three!
土天重花でも やるっきゃないさ
Even through the Dotenjuuka, we have to do it.
今宣戦布告
Declaring war now
こんなにドデッカイ！ 希望乗せて
This huge! Carrying hope
ドデッカイ さあ行こう！
Huge! Let's go!
5人合わせて
All five together
秘密結社holoX 参上！
Secret Society holoX, arrives!
でござる〜！
De-gozaru~!
てえてえはお預けです
Wholesomeness is on hold.
いや、仲の良さは認めるけど
Well, I admit we're close, but...
統べるはエデンの星だから！
Because we rule Eden's Star!
さあ作戦会議日和です！ (え〜！？)
It's a perfect day for a strategy meeting! (Eh!?)
なんなら言えば宇宙一なんですが…
Actually, you could say we're number one in the universe...
まず風呂入って？
First, take a bath?
日本中を腹黒さ…
Across Japan, our black-hear...
お呼び全人類を 虜にしたのち
I mean, after making all of humanity captives
いい汗かきましょ
Let's break a good sweat
まだ見ぬ場所まで
to places we've never seen before
ドデカク行こうぜ！
Let's go big!
ちょーゆめドデッカイ！ ぜったいぜったい
Super dream huge! Definitely, definitely
海を超えドデッカイ！ ぜったいせーので
Huge across the sea! One-two-three!
荒波でも守るっきゃないさ
Even in rough seas, we have to protect it.
愛の声が聞こえる
I hear the voice of love.
さあ行くぞドデッカイ！ 不安捨てて
Now let's go huge! Cast aside anxiety
ドデッカイ さあ行こう！
Huge! Let's go!
強者だって 怯まず立ち向かうぜ
Even against the strong, we'll face them without flinching.
人生簡単には うまくいかないけど
Life doesn't go easily, but...
我ら力を合わせれば
If we combine our strength...
きっと行けるはず！ いざ！
We should surely be able to go! Now!
ちょーゆめドデッカイ！ ぜったいぜったい
Super dream huge! Definitely, definitely
手合わせてドデッカイ！ ぜったいせーので
Clasping hands, huge! One-two-three!
土天重花でも やるっきゃないさ
Even through the Dotenjuuka, we have to do it.
今宣戦布告
Declaring war now
こんなにドデッカイ！ 希望乗せて
This huge! Carrying hope
ドデッカイ さあ行こう！
Huge! Let's go!
5人合わせて
All five together
秘密結社holoX
Secret Society holoX
待っていてね みんなのため 参上！
Wait for us, for everyone's sake, we arrive!
でござる〜！
De-gozaru~!
holoX!
3周年、始まるよー！
Our 3rd anniversary starts now!
というわけで、3周年ですね、みなさん。
So, it's our 3rd anniversary, everyone.
3周年！
3rd anniversary!
3周年ライブのハッシュタグはこちらでございます。
The hashtag for this 3rd anniversary live is this one.
ポストしてください。お願いします。
Please post with it. Thank you.
ということで早速なんですけれども、グッズ紹介をしたいと思います！
Alright then, I'd like to jump right into introducing the merchandise!
いえーい！早い！
Yay! That was fast!
グッズ紹介を今回していただきます、皆さんでございます。一人ずつ自己紹介をお願いします。
The ones introducing the merch this time are all of you. Please introduce yourselves one by one.
刮目せよ！
Behold!
イエス、マイダーク！
Yes, My Dark!
吾輩のお名前は…ラプラス…忘れて…ダークネスだ！
Wagahai's name is... Laplus... forgot it... Darknesss da!
覚えろよ！
Remember it!
はい、はい。一言とか言いたいことないですか？
Yes, yes. Any last words or something you want to say?
一言？みんな来てくれてありがとうな！
Last words? Thanks for coming, everyone!
あー、いいですね。ありがとう言えましたね。ありがとう言えてえらい。ということで続いては、こより！
Ah, nice. You said thank you. Good girl. Moving on, Koyori!
はい！
Yes!
みんな、こんこよー！holoXの頭脳、博衣こよりだよー！
Hi everyone, Kon-Koyo! HoloX's Brain, Hakui Koyori da yo!
3周年、ここよー！
3rd anniversary, Koyo-koyo!
ここよー！
Koyo-koyo!
ありがとー！よろしくお願いいたします。
Thank you! Please take care of me!
素晴らしい。よろしくお願いいたします。はい、そしてクロヱ！
Wonderful. Please take care of me. Yes, and next, Chloe!
バクバクバクーンなーま！秘密結社holoXの掃除屋インターン、沙花叉クロヱです！
Bakubakubakūn-nawa! Secret Society holoX's cleaner intern, Sakamata Chloe desu!
浴びません！洗いません！
I won't take a bath! I won't wash!
いただきまーす！
Eat up!
食べまーす！
I'll eat!
食べまーす！立てやー！
I'll eat! Stand up!
いただきまーす。うわ、あったまわるー。そして、いろは！
Eat up. Ugh, that was dumb. And next, Iroha!
はい！
Yes!
こんばんはでござるー！holoXの用心棒侍の風真いろはでござるー！
Good evening, degozaru! HoloX's bodyguard samurai, Kazama Iroha degozaru!
（かっこいいポーズ）すっ！
(Cool pose) Su!
一言、一言。
One last word, one last word.
今年もこれからもかっこいいです！よろしくお願いします！
This year and from now on, I'll be cool! Please treat me well!
嘘だー！かわいい系ー！
That's a lie! You're just being cute!
3周年なのになんで嘘ついてるの！
It's our 3rd anniversary and you're calling me a liar?!
そんなあなたわ？はい、それではみなさんありがとうございます。
And you are? Alright, thank you everyone.
本日の進行はこの私、鷹嶺ルイが務めさせていただきます。
I, Takane Lui, will be your MC today.
務めさせていただく？そんなキャラじゃなかったけど、務めさせていただきます。
I'll be handling this? That's not my character, but I'll be doing my best.
頑張りますのでよろしくお願いします！
I'll do my best, so please take care of me!
ってかさ、鷹嶺。吾輩たちさ、holoXなんだけど、なんでこんなセットなわけよ？
Hey, hey, Takane. We're holoX, so why is the set like this?
よくお気づきで。やっぱり3周年にもなるとみなさんそういうところに気づくんですね。
Good catch! After 3 years, you guys notice things like this.
誰でも気づくわ！普通に縦に立つのおかしいわ！
Anyone would notice! We're just standing vertically, it's weird!
今回の配信ですけれども、3Dライブがありまして、歌がメインでございます。
This stream is a 3D Live, and singing is the main part.
そうだね！歌って踊ったよ！
Right! We sang and danced!
ですが、普通のグッズ紹介をしても面白くないということで！
But, just doing a normal merch intro wouldn't be fun!
いやいいって！普通にやろうぜ！普通でいいですよ！
No, no, normal is fine! Just do it normally! Normal is fine!
ということでなんとグッズ紹介、大喜利をしていただきます！
Therefore, for the merch intro... we'll be doing Oogiri!
やめろー！大喜利なんて大嫌いだー！
Stop it! We hate Oogiri!
ありがとうございます。3年間の全てをここに出してください。
Thank you. Please give it your all here after these 3 years.
まだ1曲しかやってないのに！1曲しかないのにクソゲーしようとしてる！
We haven't even done one song yet! Only one song and you're making us play this kusoge!
大喜利は1問しかやりませんから。全部出し切っていただかないと。
We'll only do one question for the Oogiri. You have to give it your all.
その1問でどれだけ怪我をすると思ってるんですか！本当にですよ、3周年ですよ！
Do you know how much damage that one question will do?! It's our 3rd anniversary!
あいつやらないからね！傷つくの俺らだけだった！
She isn't even doing it! We're the only ones getting hurt!
まあまあまあ。頑張ってほしいのは、そうだな、クロヱさんかな？
Well, well. I'm especially looking forward to... Chloe-san, I guess?
何でですかちょっと！お題は？お題は？
Why me?! Hey, what's the prompt? What's the prompt?!
一番頑張っていただければなと思います。じゃあお題。あ、早速やりたいということで。
I hope you'll do your best. Alright, the prompt. Oh, you want to do it right away?
お題を言えよさっさと！
Just tell us the prompt already!
お題はこちらです。「最高のholoX周年グッズ、何が入っている？」
The prompt is: "What is inside the best holoX anniversary goods?"
やりづれー！これから紹介するのに！
That's hard! We have to promote them after this!
ということで元気よく、挙手制でよろしくお願いします！
Alright, please raise your hands energetically!
そんな奴いねーよ！
No one's doing that!
はい、みなさん挙手制でお願いします。はい、一番元気な、いろはさん！
Alright, raise your hands! Oh, Iroha-san, the most energetic one!
いける！元気中！いきますよ！
I can do it! Full of energy! Here I go!
最高のholoX周年グッズ、何が入っている？ 光ってかっこいいやつ！
What is inside the best holoX anniversary goods? Something that shines and looks cool!
めっちゃ抽象的！小学生か！
That's so abstract! Are you a primary schooler?!
抽象的なのね。もっと具体的なことを考えて...
That's quite abstract. Think of something more concrete...
...こよーさん直してきてください。
...Koyori-san, please come back with a better one.
はい。続いて、お、早いですね。
Alright. Next... oh, you're fast.
こよーさん、よろしくお願いします。いきますよ。
Koyori-san, please go ahead. Here we go.
最高のholoX周年グッズ、何が入ってる？
What's in the best holoX anniversary goods?
脱ぎたての靴下。
Freshly worn socks.
お前だけだろ！誰の脱ぎたてだ？
That's just you! Whose worn ones?
こよりは別にいらないけど...
I don't really need them myself, but...
なんか、昔も靴下の話してなかった？
Wait, didn't we talk about socks before too?
いろはの靴下嗅ぎたいって言ってたよね。
You were saying you wanted to smell Iroha's socks.
いろはの靴下嗅ぎたいって言ってた。
I said I wanted to smell Iroha's socks.
リスに汚されてく...
They're being tainted by the Assistants...
怖いよ〜。
That's scary~
ランダム要素があるね。はいはいはい。
There's a random element. I see, I see.
では、続いてラプ様。いきますよ。
Then, next is Lap-sama. Here we go.
最高のholoX周年グッズ、何が入ってる？
What's in the best holoX anniversary goods?
それはもちろん...
That's of course...
吾輩だ！
Me!
え？嬉しいでしょ？
Eh? You'd be happy, right?
何分割？何分割？
Into how many pieces? How many pieces?
限定一名？待って、何分割に入る？
Limited to one person? Wait, how many pieces?
何分割する前提なんだよ！
Why are you assuming I'll be divided?!
この縞模様をね。
These stripes here.
角は切れないからね。
The horns won't be cut, though.
角が切れないなら体は切れるってこと？
If horns can't be cut, does that mean the body can?
そんなこと言ってないでしょ！揚げ足取んな！
I didn't say that! Don't twist my words!
一人だけだよ。
Only one person gets you.
お前らだけは欲しいって言えよ！
At least you guys should say you want me!
ここはいいけど... いらないらしいよ。
This part is fine, but... looks like nobody wants you.
嬉しいけど、汚くなりそうだもんな。
I'd be happy, but it seems like it would get messy.
こよりにAI作ってもらえばいいんじゃない？
Why not have Koyori make an AI of you?
AIラプラス？いいじゃん。
AI Laplus? That's a good one.
単価高くなるけどね。
The unit price would be high, though.
文章3000分を今から10日以内に読んで...
You'll have to read 3,000 sentences within 10 days...
...収録してもらって、学習させて。
...record them, and let it learn.
やめとこっか。
Let's forget about it.
やめときましょうか。
Let's forget it.
はい！ではクロエさん、いきますよ。
Yes! Then, Chloe-san, here we go.
最高のholoX周年グッズ、何が入ってる？
What's in the best holoX anniversary goods?
ギフト券100万円分。
1 million yen worth of gift certificates.
無理だろ。ダメだろ。現実的に考えたらね。
That's impossible. No way. Thinking realistically.
ギフト券なのね。何にでもなるし、嬉しい。
Gift certificates, huh. They can be anything. Nice.
でもholoXの周年グッズだよ？
But it's a holoX anniversary item, right?
あれじゃない？ラプだらけの...
How about... full of Lap...
山だらけ。ヤマダラケ。いらない！
Full of Yamada. Yamada-rake. We don't need it!
なんでだよ！可愛いだろ！
Why not?! It's cute!
あれ、ちょっと俺も欲しいみたいに言ってたから。
Wait, you were saying you wanted it too.
一人だけだよ！山だらけの...
Only one person! Full of Yamada...
これじゃまだグッズ紹介できないな。
We still can't introduce the goods at this rate.
はい！わかった！
Yes! I've got it!
お、では、いろはさん、どうぞ。
Oh, then, Iroha-san, please.
じゃ、わかった。あったかいやつ！
Okay, I've got it. Something warm!
だからまだ抽象的なのよ。可愛いけどさ。
Like I said, that's still abstract. Even if it's cute.
ちょっと待ってくださいよ！
Wait a minute!
お前だよ、ルイ！
It's your turn, Lui!
そこにルイさん！お願いします。
Lui-san over there! Please.
最後にじゃあルイさん、まとめてください。
Lastly, Lui-san, please wrap it all up.
本当ですよ。やり、やれ、やれ！何が入ってる？
Truly. Do, do it, do it! What's in it?
考えてねーじゃねーか！
You haven't thought of anything!
えーっと、みんなのランダム直筆サイン！
Um, random hand-signed autographs from everyone!
本当に欲しいやつじゃねーか！
That's something people actually want!
それはめちゃくちゃ欲しいけど...
We'd want that like crazy, but...
確かに欲しいけど、何個も買っちゃうよ。
It's true, but people would buy so many.
限定一個は全員分とか...
Like, one limited one with everyone's...
一個は全員分とか...
One with everyone's sign...
ああ、欲しいよみんな！
Ah, everyone would want that!
リアルなやつ言わないでよ！
Don't say something so realistic!
やば、欲しいじゃん、5人分。
Crap, I want it, for all 5 of us.
1人っていうより、5人でっていうのが特別だよね。
Rather than just one person, all five is special.
一個一個は割とチャンスあるから。
Each one has a fair chance.
伏線だと思われちゃう。違いますからね。
They'll think it's a hint. It's not, okay.
ねえ見て見て！トレンド1位になってます！
Hey, look, look! We're #1 on trending!
うわー！ありがとう！トレンド1位ありがとう！
Whoa! Thank you! Thank you for #1 on trending!
ということで、もう私も限界だしみんなも限界だし...
So, I'm at my limit and everyone else is too...
本当だよ。潮時だよ。
It's true. It's high time.
私が紹介したいと思います。みんなありがとうございました。
I'll introduce them myself. Thank you, everyone.
それでは、1つ目はこちらでございます！ドドン！
Then, here is the first one! Ta-da!
言っちゃった。
She said it.
ラバーマットです！
It's a rubber mat!
イェーイ！
Yay!
今、需要ね、すごく高まっております。
The demand for these is very high right now.
ラバーマット。高値だけにね。
A rubber mat. Just like my high name.
前回に続いてイラストを大きく使用したマットになってます。
Like before, it features the illustration prominently.
私たちholoXメンバー5人の一瞬を切り取ったイラストです。
It's an illustration capturing a moment of us 5.
イラストは、小豚さんでございます。ありがとう！
The illustration is by Kobuta-san. Thank you!
めっちゃ可愛いよね！
It's super cute, isn't it!
オフ写とかでラバーマット欲しいって人いますからね。
People often want rubber mats of off-shots.
机とかにもね。可愛いね。髪の毛最高にいいよね。
For desks and things. Cute. The hair is amazing.
素敵なイラストなので、ぜひ皆さんもデスクで使ってください。
It's a lovely illustration, so please use it at your desks.
もう時間がないらしいので、私の方で全部紹介します。
We're out of time, so I'll introduce everything myself.
えー！不公平！俺一人だけいないじゃん！
Eh! Unfair! Only I'm not shown!
何言ってんだよ、お前しか映ってないよ、今。
What are you saying? You're the only one on screen.
みんな紹介したい！
We all want to introduce them!
まあまあ。コメント欄でもね、みんなを出せって。
Now, now. People in the comments want to see everyone.
ラバーマット
Rubber Mat
描いて... 描いてはない。うん。
I didn't... I didn't paint it. Yeah.
じゃあね、あの、みんなで紹介していきましょう。
Now then, let's introduce them all together.
やったー！
Yay!
大喜利用のセットはいらないと思いますので、消しちゃいましょう。
I don't think we'll need the comedy set anymore, so let's make it disappear.
消える！？
It's disappearing?!
さかささん、さっき練習したやつ、いきますよ。
Sakasa-san, I'm going to do the one we practiced earlier.
なにそれ？
What's that?
せーの！
Ready, set...
パン！
Bam!
なんだなんだ？
What's this, what's this?
消えたでしょ、これで。
They're gone now, see?
消えてねー！
They're not gone!
消えてねーだろ。ふざけんなよ。
They're not gone. Stop messing around.
消えてない、消えてない。
They're not gone, they're not gone.
そういうミスみたいになってんぞ。違うな、間違ってるぞ。
It looks like you just failed the trick. No, you're doing it wrong.
消せー！
Disappear!
味しめてんじゃねーよ、ルイ。
Don't get too carried away, Lui.
やめてください。
Please stop.
あれやめよ。あ、ちゃんとね。
Let's stop that. Oh, okay, for real this time.
あったあった！消えた！
They're gone! They disappeared!
あのセットマジなんだった？
Seriously, what was that set for?
わからん。
No idea.
はい。ここからはね、あの、茶番もなしで、
All right. From here on, no more skits,
あの、ちゃんと紹介をしていきたいと思います。
we'll introduce the items properly.
お願いしますよ。
Please do.
それでは、こよりさん、お願いいたします。
Well then, Koyori-san, please go ahead.
はい！
Yes!
モチーフキーホルダー（全5種）
Motif Keychain (5 types total)
2つ目のグッズはこちら、モチーフキーホルダーです！
The second item is this: the motif keychain!
こちらね、さっきもやってましたが、2周年記念のときに実装されたもので、
As we were doing earlier, these were implemented for our 2nd anniversary,
例のあれを象ったキーホルダーとなっております。
and they're keychains modeled after *that* thing.
例のあれ。
That thing.
満を持して登場いただきました。
They've finally made their appearance.
なんでこれなの！？
Why this?!
メンバーごとのね、カラーで再現しておりまして、
They're reproduced in each member's color,
カバンやポーチにつけてさりげなくholoXアピールができるとっても可愛いグッズとなっております。
and they're very cute items that you can attach to your bag or pouch to casually show your holoX pride.
ホワイト版なんだね、ホワイト版。
It's the white version, the white version.
あ、そうね。
Ah, right.
これ、ルイしか使ってないやつ...
This is the one only Lui uses...
いやいや！一回だけ使った...
No, no! I only used it once...
吾輩も2回ぐらい...
I used it about twice too...
KOのモノマネするときに...
When imitating KO...
はい、じゃあ3つ目、クロヱ！
Okay, now for the third item, Chloe!
はい！
Yes!
リュック
Backpack
3つ目はリュックです！
The third item is a backpack!
これ普通によくない？
Isn't this actually really good?
頑丈で通勤や通学にも使える大きな容量のリュックになっております。イェーイ。
It's a large-capacity backpack that's sturdy and can be used for commuting to work or school. Yay.
サイドや背中部分にもさりげなくXモチーフが散りばめられています。
X motifs are also casually scattered on the sides and back.
これこよりさんのパソコンとか入れられるんじゃない？
Couldn't you fit Koyori-san's computer in here?
そうですね、今日も持ち込んでおりますので。
That's true, I brought it with me today as well.
助かる。そのまま吾輩のことも入れてもらっていいですか。
That helps. Could you put me in there too?
最大限の重荷として使わせてもらいます。
I'll take you as the maximum possible burden.
ひびきにしまう。はい。
I'll put you in Hibiki. Okay.
次、いろはちゃん！
Next, Iroha-chan!
はい！
Yes!
ブロマイドケース
Bromide Case
4つ目はブロマイドケースです！
The fourth item is a bromide case!
複製手書きメッセージ入りの、メッセージはですね、皆さん開いてからのお楽しみとなっております！
It comes with a duplicated handwritten message. The message is something for everyone to look forward to after opening it!
エモい。エモくなっております。
It's emotional. It's become quite emotional.
イラストはラバーマットと同じ小豚先生のものになっております。
The illustration is by Kobuta-sensei, the same as the rubber mat.
エモすぎ。切り替えできるんじゃない？
Too emotional. Can't you switch them out?
切り替え可能。中身はぜひ、皆さんお手元に届いてから見てくださいね。
You can switch them. Please check the contents yourself once it arrives.
みんな成長したからね、文字もね。
Everyone's grown, including our handwriting.
そうね。まあまあ。
That's true. Well, sort of.
まぁまぁっていうな！
Don't say "sort of"!
さて、新曲の「暁光クロニクル」はみんな聴いていただけたでしょうか！
Now then, I hope everyone has had a chance to listen to our new song, "Gyokou Chronicle"!
暁光クロニクル
Gyokou Chronicle
聴いたー！
We heard it!
今日は聴けるんですか？
Can we hear it today?
聞けるんですか？どうなんですか、クロヱさん。
Can we hear it? What's the deal, Chloe-san?
聞けるわけ... 聞けますよね？え、聞けないパターンってあるんですか、これから。
There's no way... We can hear it, right? Wait, is there a scenario where we can't hear it from now?
聞けないんじゃない？
Maybe we can't?
えー！聞けない可能性あるんじゃない？
What?! There's a chance we can't hear it?
出したまんま。
We just released it.
ま、もしかしたらね、今日は聞けないかもしれないんですけども、そうだとしても、公式チャンネルでMVや各種ストリーミングサイトで聴くことができます！
Well, maybe we won't be able to hear it today, but even if that's the case, you can listen to the MV on the official channel and on various streaming sites!
で、moraさんで、ハイレゾまとめ購入をしていただくと、ここでしか聞けないキャンペーンボイスもあるとのことですよ。
Also, if you purchase the high-res bundle on mora, there's a campaign voice that you can only hear there.
秘密結社holoX 3周年「暁光クロニクル」リリース記念ボイス
Secret Society holoX 3rd Anniversary "Gyokou Chronicle" Release Commemorative Voice
さらに「暁光クロニクル」のリリース記念ボイスも販売中なので、皆さんぜひ聞いてください、お願いします。
Plus, the "Gyokou Chronicle" release commemorative voice is also on sale, so please give it a listen, everyone.
お願いします。
Please do.
そして今、公式チャンネルのメンバーシップに入ってくれたら、吾輩たちの...
And right now, if you join the official channel membership, our...
秘密結社holoX 3周年記念！公式メンバーシップ限定壁紙・限定絵文字
Secret Society holoX 3rd Anniversary! Official Membership Limited Wallpapers & Limited Emojis
キービジュアル！さっきのイラストだね。を使用した限定の絵文字や壁紙が使えます。
Key visual! That illustration from earlier. You can use limited emojis and wallpapers featuring it.
メンバーからの限定スタンプが使えます。
You can use limited stamps from the members.
今！
Now!
今ナウです。
Now, now.
使ってる！使って！みんな。
People are using them! Use them, everyone!
ねえ、holoXの顔、コピペできるから。
Look, you can copy-paste the faces of holoX.
コピペ、コピペ。
Copy-paste, copy-paste.
ルイ、ルイ、ラプラス、クロヱ、クロヱ。
Lui, Lui, La+, Chloe, Chloe.
コピペやめて。
Stop saying copy-paste.
こより、こよりもできるね。
Koyori, Koyori can do it too.
お願いします。
Please.
やってくれてるかな？いいですね。
Are you guys doing it? Nice.
ということで、3周年ライブは始まったばかりでございます！
And so, the 3rd anniversary live has only just begun!
次はなんと、デュエットリレーになっております！
Next up is, incredibly, a duet relay!
初めてじゃない？誰と誰？
Is this the first time? Who and who?
ラプラスと誰がやるんだ？
Who is La+ going to do it with?
ルイと誰？ルイ、いろは？
Lui and who? Lui, Iroha?
ここからはね、ノンストップで盛り上げていきますので、応援よろしくお願いします！
From here on, we're going to keep the excitement going non-stop, so please support us!
お願いします！
Please!
最初の組み合わせはね、今匂わせをしていた2人なのか？
Is the first pair the two we were just hinting at?
誰だ！？
Who is it?!
いくぞ！
Here we go!
ルイ、ラプ、3周年！
Lui, Lap, 3rd anniversary!
イェーイ！
Yay!
鷹嶺ルイ「......やっと見つけた」
Takane Lui: "......Finally found you."
......やっと見つけた
......Finally found you.
ラプラス・ダークネス「吾輩を探していたのか？」
La+ Darknesss: "Were you looking for me?"
吾輩を探していたのか？
Were you looking for me?
私の、
For mine,
私たちの「夢」のために。
For our 'dream'.
そうか……。
I see...
ならちょうどいい、
Then it's perfect.
吾輩にも力を貸せ。
Lend me your strength as well.
この世界を手に入れる。
To take over this world.
わかった……。力を貸そう。
I understand... I will lend you my strength.
手を出してくれ。
Hold out your hand.
ええ。
Yes.
これで吾輩たちは共犯者だ。
Now, we are accomplices.
ヴィラン
作詞・作曲：てにをは
Villain
Lyrics & Composition: Teniwoha
きっと手を繋ぐだけで ゾッとされる
Just holding hands would surely make them shudder.
レット・レース 一抜けたら 通報されるわ
If I quit this rat race, they'll report me.
ニュートラルじゃない ただの僕さ
I'm not neutral, I'm just me.
XとかYとか
X or Y and all that.
べき論者様は 語れど 胎内
The moralists speak, but deep inside,
届かぬ君を 侵害するって いくら知ってる
They know just how much they violate the unreachable you.
Oh, Mr. Crazy ヴィラン ヴィラン
Oh, Mr. Crazy Villain, Villain
夜行性の花びら
Nocturnal flower petals
違う服着て
Wearing different clothes,
君の前では 男子のふりする
I pretend to be a boy in front of you.
拝啓 ドクター ヴィラン ヴィラン
Dear Doctor Villain, Villain
迎えに来て下さい
Please come and get me.
顔も知らない 誰かにとって
To someone whose face I don't even know,
僕はもう ヴィラン
I'm already a villain.
ヴィラン
Villain
ヴィラン ヴィラン
Villain, Villain
ヴィラン
Villain
蛇化脱愛 蛇化脱愛
Snaking out of love, snaking out of love,
揚げ句の果ての
and in the end,
ヴィラン
Villain
逸脱の成れの果てを
Waiting for the end
待って 膝を隠す
of this deviance, hiding my knees.
惜しげも無く
Even if I expose myself
曝け出したって 言う甲斐ないの
without regret, it's not worth saying.
偽世の空から ポシュリン・ポシュ
Poshurin posh from the sky of this fake world
真逆の答を ボシュイン・ボシュ
Boshuin posh for the opposite answer
憎悪も愛も 蛇は身を結ぶ
Both hatred and love, the snake bears fruit.
触ってんじゃねえよ 多種多様の性
Don't touch me, all you diverse sexualities.
悲しい悲しい話をしようか
Shall we tell a sad, sad story?
ゼラチン質の
About the gelatinous...
Oh, Mr. Crazy ヴィラン ヴィラン
Oh, Mr. Crazy Villain, Villain
可能性に幸あれ
Blessings upon the possibilities.
僕のハートを暴いて
Uncover my heart
秘密の 嫉妬を奪わせてよ
and let me take away the secret jealousy.
拝啓 ドクター ヴィラン ヴィラン
Dear Doctor Villain, Villain
歪んでいてもいいのに
It's okay to be distorted.
誰も知らない
A secret poem
知られたくない 秘密の詩
that no one knows, and I don't want anyone to know.
素晴らしい規約と共に
A song dedicated along
捧げる歌
with wonderful rules.
惚れ惚れしてよ
Admire me, pull me in,
惹き手 抗えぬ クラスに
to a class that cannot be resisted.
残酷なまま
A cruel,
解き放てない 蜜の味
unreleaseable taste of honey.
わい雑 国々に
Dancing in vulgar countries,
踊るポップ隊の ああ
oh, the pop troupe.
Oh, Mr. Crazy ヴィラン ヴィラン
Oh, Mr. Crazy Villain, Villain
夜行性の花びら
Nocturnal flower petals
違う服着て
Wearing different clothes,
君の前では 男子のふりをする
I pretend to be a boy in front of you.
拝啓 ドクター ヴィラン ヴィラン
Dear Doctor Villain, Villain
ここで会おう
Let's meet here.
顔も知らない 誰かにとって
To someone whose face I don't even know,
僕はもう ヴィラン
I'm already a villain.
ヴィラン
Villain
蛇化脱愛 蛇化脱愛
Snaking out of love, snaking out of love,
揚げ句の果ての
and in the end,
ヴィラン
Villain
やあ「博衣こより」、研究に精が出るね。
Hey, "Hakui Koyori." Working hard on your research, I see.
またあなたですか……。
You again...
君が自由にできる環境は用意できたよ。
I've prepared an environment where you can work freely.
それに、面白いリーダーもね。
And an interesting leader, too.
ふん。
Hmph.
それに、見たくない？
Besides, don't you want to see it?
自分の「研究」が世界中に広がっていく姿を。
Your "research" spreading across the entire world.
ふむ……。
Fumu...
私は興味あるけどなぁ。
I'm certainly interested.
なるほど……。そこまで言うなら付き合ってあげましょう。
I see... If you're going that far, then I'll join you.
大丈夫ですか？ 僕は劇薬かもしれませんよ……？
Are you sure? I might be a potent poison...?
ははっ、
Haha,
毒を食らわばってね。
As the saying goes, "might as well eat the poison."
足りないものなんだ　僕らの人生
What is it we're lacking in our lives?
正解どこなんだ　探せよ探せ
Where is the right answer? Search for it, search!
例外ない　二進も三進も　劣化以外ない　劣化以外ない
No exceptions, stuck in a rut, nothing but degradation...
三味腐せげ　空々回れ
Devouring flavor, spinning in vain.
当て処どこだ　僕らの人生
Where is our destination? In our lives.
混載どこだ　隠せよ隠せ
Where is the congestion? Hide it, hide it!
盛大ない　和気藹々　制裁代々　生産性ない
No grand gala, no friendly harmony, sanctions for generations, no productivity.
後悔どこだ　笑えよ笑え
Where is the regret? Laugh, laugh!
僕らレシピは　辛味調味　弱気ジャンキー
Our recipe is spicy seasoning and a timid junkie.
だんだん強がって　泥々に伏す
Steadily acting tough, we fall into the mud.
毒々　飲み込んで
Gulping down the poison...
苦しんで　泣いて　吐き出せない
Suffering, crying, unable to spit it out.
ベノベノム　さよなら
Veno-venom, goodbye.
不安勢　孤独　毒　流るる
Anxiety and loneliness, the poison flows.
冗態ないね　痛い痛いの飛んでけ
It's not a joke, pain pain go away.
存在感　猛毒　溢るる
Presence, the deadly poison overflows.
愛！　愛！　曝け出せ　ベノム
Love! Love! Expose it, Venom.
めっ！
Bad!
最高点　どっだ　僕らの人生
Where is the peak? In our lives.
満点点　どっだ　鏡よ鏡
Where is the perfect score? Mirror, mirror...
オンリーナイ　頂辺回って　狼狽ないの　温厚本望
Only night, spinning at the top, no panic, gentle satisfaction.
オーバーロード気だ　煽れよ煽れ
It feels like an overload, egg it on, egg it on!
僕ら中身は　無味無味　無機ジャンキー
Our inside is tasteless, inorganic junkie.
どんどん強がって　バラバラに伏す
Increasingly acting tough, falling apart.
毒々　飲み込んで
Gulping down the poison...
苦しんで　泣いて　逃げ出せない
Suffering, crying, unable to escape.
ベノベノム　さよなら
Veno-venom, goodbye.
不安心　孤独　毒　流るる
Anxious heart and loneliness, the poison flows.
冗態ないね　痛い痛いの飛んでけ
It's not a joke, pain pain go away.
存在感　既毒　毒　欲しがれる
Presence, the existing poison, I can crave the poison.
愛！　愛！　曝け出せ　ベノム
Love! Love! Expose it, Venom.
めっ！
Bad!
もう圧政　孤独　毒　回るる
Already tyranny, loneliness, the poison spins.
冗態ないね　痛い痛いのシクシク
It's not a joke, pain pain, sobbing.
存在魔性　毒々　消えるる
Demonic presence, the poison disappears.
愛！　愛！　曝け出せ　ベノム
Love! Love! Expose it, Venom.
不安心　孤独　毒　流るる
Anxious heart and loneliness, the poison flows.
冗態ないね　痛い痛いの飛んでけ
It's not a joke, pain pain go away.
存在感　既毒　毒　欲しがれる
Presence, the existing poison, I can crave the poison.
愛！　愛！　曝け出せ　ベノム
Love! Love! Expose it, Venom.
めっ！
Bad!
曝け出せ　ベノム
Expose it, Venom.
めっ！
Bad!
曝け出せ　ベノム
Expose it, Venom.
めっ！
Bad!
ふふっ　ふふふっ　楽しいなる！
Fufu, fufufu, this is getting fun!
ちょちょっと！それ何してるの！
Wait, wait! What are you doing?!
何って……実験？
What? ...An experiment?
それぜっっっったいダメだよ！なんかめちゃくちゃ嫌な濁り方してるって！
That's absolutely no good! It's turning a really nasty murky color!
え？それがいいんじゃん
Eh? But that's the best part.
やめようよ！それ掃除するの沙花叉の仕事になるんだから！！
Stop it! Cleaning that up is going to be my job!!
ふふふふ……知ってる？奇跡も！魔法も！あるらしいよ！
Fufufufu... You know? Miracles! And magic! They supposedly exist!
もうすでにおかしくなってんじゃん！もーーー！
You've already gone crazy! Geez!
伝えあった　心の温度を　そっと
Softly, the warmth of the hearts we shared...
大事そうに　抱え歩いていた
I walked on, holding it as if it were precious.
答えのない　願いの中で
Within a wish that has no answer...
言葉は未来変えて
Words will change the future.
幼い頃ずっと　夢に見ていた
I had always dreamed of it as a child.
私にはまだ遠いけど　君がいれば
It's still far from me, but if you're here...
少しは強く
I feel like I can
なれる気がして
become a little stronger,
明日の色に
overlapping with
重なった
the colors of tomorrow.
呼んだ希望を辿って
Following the hope I called for,
止めた世界の越えた
I crossed the world that I had stopped.
諦めない想い
Feelings that won't give up,
いつしか心繋げた
our hearts were connected before I knew it.
泣いてたって笑って
Even if I'm crying, I'll smile,
明日迎えに行こう
let's go greet tomorrow.
決めた誓い
The vow I made,
辛くたって
even if it's painful,
倒れても
even if I fall,
君の心を
to protect
守るため
your heart.
記憶のない
In the flow of time
時の流れに
without memory,
きっと求めていた
I'm sure the warmth I was seeking
温かさはあって
was there.
包まれた
The moment
瞬間全ての
I was embraced, all my
想いは君へ巡る
feelings come back to you.
空に向かって
I ran towards the sky
走り手にした
and grabbed
幾つもの尊い光を
many precious lights,
胸にしまって
keeping them in my heart,
私の中の
transforming them
輝きに変え
into brilliance inside me.
迷いを全部
Let's release all
放て共
our hesitations together.
世界の見えない
Exiting the world's invisible,
入り組んだ迷路を抜け
intricate maze,
君が流した涙で
my heart woke up
心目覚めた
with the tears you shed.
そして知った世界は
And the world I came to know
こんなにもまで綺麗で
is this beautiful,
新しい可能性を
it will surely create
生むだろう
new possibilities,
時のカケラの
from the wish
願いから
of a shard of time.
救い信じて
Feelings that cracked,
割れた想い
believing in salvation,
私が
I stand
始まりに立って
at the beginning,
君の笑顔を
I'll bring back
取り戻すよ
your smile,
真実の奇跡になって
becoming a true miracle.
呼んだ希望を辿って
Following the hope I called for,
止めた世界の越えた
I crossed the world that I had stopped.
諦めない想い
Feelings that won't give up,
いつしか心繋げた
our hearts were connected before I knew it.
泣いてたって笑って
Even if I'm crying, I'll smile,
明日迎えに行こう
let's go greet tomorrow.
決めた誓い
The vow I made,
辛くたって
even if it's painful,
倒れても
even if I fall,
君の心を
to protect
守るため
your heart.
君の
I'll be
そばに居よう
by your side.
なかなかやるでござるな！
You're doing quite well!
そっちこそ！
You too!
いや、戦闘員がいると楽だねー
Man, having a combatant around makes things easy.
ん？クロヱ殿サボってるでござるか？
Hmm? Are you slacking off, Chloe-dono?
サボってないよ、ほら戦ってる戦ってる
I'm not slacking! See, I'm fighting, I'm fighting!
……そうでござるか？
...Is that so?
……であれば、どんどん行くでござるよ！
...In that case, let's keep going!
わぁーいらくちーん！めちゃハッピー！
Yay, how easy! I'm so happy!
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
君の胸の奥まで
to the depths of your heart,
届くようなメロディ
a melody that will reach you,
奏でるよ
I'll play it for you.
ハッピーシンセサイザ / 作詞・作曲：BETTI
Happy Synthesizer / Lyrics & Composition: BETTI
儚く散った淡い片思い
A fleeting, pale unrequited love,
笑い話だね今語れば
it's a funny story now that I talk about it.
リズムもすべて輝いて見えた
Everything, even the rhythm, looked bright,
あの日々が綺麗に回ってるよ
those days are turning beautifully.
我慢することだけ覚えなきゃいけないの？
Do I have to learn only how to endure things?
大人になって頂戴ねならなくていいよ
"Please grow up" - no, you don't have to.
知らないことばかり知らないの見て言えなくて
So many things I don't know, unable to say "I don't know,"
対面相合して俯いてごめんね
facing each other, looking down, I'm sorry.
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
君の胸の奥まで
to the depths of your heart,
届くようなメロディ
a melody that will reach you,
奏でるよ
I'll play it for you.
...つまらない
...boring
タテマエや　ヤなこと全部
facades and all the bad things
消してあげるから　この音で
I'll wipe them away with this sound
なんのとりえもない　僕に唯一
There's only one thing I, who has no merit,
少しだけ出来ること
am able to do a little bit of
心踊らせる　飾らない言葉
The unadorned words that make my heart dance,
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them with electronic sounds
好きになること理屈なんかじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about logic,
こじつけなんかいらないんじゃない？
don't you think we don't need any excuses?
時代のせいと諦めたらそこまで
If you give up and blame the times, that's the end of it,
踏み出さなくちゃ何も始まらない
nothing will start unless you take a step forward
ごめんね夜分遅く　眠るところだったでしょう？
Sorry for the late hour, you were probably about to sleep, right?
驚いた私も　駆け出そうとしていた
I, who was surprised, was also about to start running out
心の裏側を　くすぐられているような
Like having the back of my heart tickled,
惹かれあう二人に　幸せな音を
giving a happy sound to the two of us who are drawn to each other
ハッピーシンセサイザ　ほらね　楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see, it's getting fun
涙拭うメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that wipes away tears
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない？別に
It's okay not to act tough, isn't it? Really,
自分に素直になればいい
you should just be honest with yourself
なんのとりえもない　僕に唯一
There's only one thing I, who has no merit,
少しだけ出来ること
am able to do a little bit of
ちょっと照れるような　単純な気持ち
The simple feelings that are a bit embarrassing,
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them with electronic sounds
ハッピーシンセサイザ　君の　胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, into the depths of your heart,
届くようなメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you
つまらないタテマエや　ヤなこと全部
The boring facades and all the bad things,
消してあげるから　この音で
I'll wipe them away with this sound
なんのとりえもない　僕に唯一
There's only one thing I, who has no merit,
少しだけ出来ること
am able to do a little bit of
心踊らせる　飾らない言葉
The unadorned words that make my heart dance,
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them with electronic sounds
ハッピーシンセサイザ　ほらね　楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see, it's getting fun
涙拭うメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that wipes away tears
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない？別に
It's okay not to act tough, isn't it? Really,
自分に素直になればいい
you should just be honest with yourself
なんのとりえもない　僕に唯一
There's only one thing I, who has no merit,
少しだけ出来ること
am able to do a little bit of
ちょっと照れるような　単純な気持ち
The simple feelings that are a bit embarrassing,
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them with electronic sounds
いろはーーーっ！スイッチ！
Iroha! Switch!
え、ラプラス殿！？
Eh, La+ dono!?
助けに来たぞ！助太刀ってやつだ！
I've come to help! I'm your backup!
助かるでござる！
That helps a lot!
でも、よく場所がわかったでござるな？
But how did you know where I was?
ふん！吾輩は総帥だぞ！
Hmph! I am the leader, after all!
そんなことより、ほら行くぞいろは！
Never mind that, come on, let's go Iroha!
おう！でござるっ！
Right! Gozaru!
Catch the Moment
そっと吐き出す溜息を吸い込んで
Sucking in the sigh gently exhaled
後悔は苦い味残して
regret leaves behind a bitter taste
いつも何で肝心なこと言えないまま
Why is it always that while I'm unable to say the important things,
次の朝日が顔出して
the next morning sun shows its face
嫌になった運命をナイフで切り刻んで
Carving up the destiny I've grown to hate with a knife,
もう一度
one more time
やり直したら君に出会えないかも
If I start over, I might not be able to meet you
僕の声が
When my voice
響いた時に始まる
resounds, it begins
イレイサブル・リミット　心臓がカウントしてる
Erasable limit, my heart is counting down
叶えても
Even if it comes true,
even if it comes true,
終わらない願い
a wish that never ends
汗をかいて走った世界の秒針は
The world's second hand, which I ran sweating alongside,
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
will one day leave me behind when I've stopped
あと何回君と笑えるの
How many more times can I laugh with you?
唱えるの...
I will sing...
試してるんだ僕も。
I'm testing it too.
Catch the Moment
1個 幸せを数える度に
Every time I count a piece of happiness,
変わっていく 未来に怯えて
getting scared of the changing future,
しまうけど 愛情の
but I'll still...
種を大切に育てよう
nurture the seeds of love with care.
分厚い雲 やがて
The thick clouds will soon
突き破るかな
break through, I wonder?
君の声が響いた
Your voice echoed,
僕は全心全霊で
and with all my heart and soul,
心臓のドアをノックしてる
I'm knocking on the door of my heart.
臆病でも
Even if I'm a coward,
開けちゃうんだよ
I'm going to open it,
信じたいから
because I want to believe.
何もないと思ったはずの
Beneath my feet, where I thought
足元にいつか
there was nothing,
深く確かな根をはやす
deep and sure roots will grow one day.
嵐の夜が来たとしても
Even if a stormy night comes,
揺らいだりはしない
I will not waver.
追いついたり 追い越したり
Catching up, overtaking,
君が不意に 分からなくなって
suddenly, I lose sight of you,
呼吸をした タイミングが 合うだけで 嬉しくなったりして
and just by our breathing syncing up, I find myself getting happy.
集めた1秒を
If I could make the seconds I've gathered
永遠にして行けたなら
last for eternity...
僕の声が響いた
My voice echoed,
時に始まる
the time it begins,
イマジナリーリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
Imaginary Limit, my heart is counting.
叶えても
Even if it's granted,
even if it's granted,
終わらない願い
the wish never ends.
汗をかいて走った
I ran, sweating,
世界の秒針が いつか止まった
the world's second hand stopped one day,
僕を置いていく あと何回
leaving me behind. How many more times
君と笑えるの
can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ僕も Catch the Moment
I'm testing it too, Catch the Moment.
逃さないよ 僕を
I won't let it get away, I'll seize
この時を掴め
this moment.
Catch the Moment
と、まぁ、こんな感じで全員そろいました……と
And so, well, that's how we've all gathered together...
こんな感じって、どんな感じですか……総帥？
What exactly do you mean by "that's how", Leader?
まぁ、こんな感じってことは、こんな感じだよね～ ラプちゃん？
Well, "that's how" means "that's how", right, Rapu-chan?
相変わらず、適当言ってるなぁ……
As usual, just saying whatever comes to mind...
まあまあ、それもholoXっぽいでござるよ
Now, now, that's just very holoX-like.
うるさい！ holoXの戦いはここからなんですー！ お前ら準備はいいか！！
Shut up! holoX's battle starts from here! Are you guys ready!?
次の曲は！
The next song is!
チルドレンレコード！！！
Children Record!!!
白いイヤホンを耳にあて 少しニヤっとして合図する
Putting on white earphones, giving a smirk as a signal.
染み込んだこの温度が ドアをノックした瞬間に
The moment this ingrained temperature knocked on the door,
危怠（きたい）になるよ まだ見えない 目を凝らして 臨む 想像
it becomes dangerous. Still unseen, I gaze intently at the envisioned imagination.
あの日躊躇した脳裏から
From the back of my mind where I hesitated that day,
「今だ、取り戻せ」とコードが鳴り出しそう
the code seems ready to ring out, "Now, take it back!"
愛おしくて
Precious,
辛くて 世界を嫌ったヒトなら
and painful... for someone who hated the world.
酷く傲慢な構成
A terribly arrogant composition
肯定しちゃ未来は生み出せない
Affirming it won't produce a future
少年少女前を向く
Boys and girls, look forward
眩む炎天すら希望論だって
Even the dizzying heat is a theory of hope
「ツレマドわせ」
“Lead astray”
三日月が赤く燃え上がる
The crescent moon burns bright red
さあさあ、コードを零号に
Now, now, set the code to zero
想像力の外側の世界へ
To the world outside our imagination
オーバーな空想戦線を
Beyond the fantasy front line
「お先にどうぞ」って舌を出す
Sticking out their tongue saying, “After you”
余裕ぶったお調子者
A cocky, upbeat person
ほら出番だパスワードで
Look, it's your turn, with the password
目を覚ましたじゃじゃ馬共
The shrews have awakened
止まらない
Unstoppable
もう夜が深くなる
The night is deepening
お子様なら燃える延長戦
If you're children, it's a burning overtime
逆境ぐらいいいさ　転ばないで
Adversity is fine, don't fall
まだまだほら、早く、早く
Not yet, look, quickly, quickly
インテンポで視線を合わせて
In tempo, meet eyes
ハイタッチでビートが鳴り出せば
And when the beat sounds with a high-five
考えてちゃ遅いでしょう？
Thinking is too slow, right?
ほら乗っかってこうぜ
Come on, let's ride it
ワンコードで視線を合わせて
With one code, meet eyes
ぶっ飛んだグルーヴが渦巻けば
And when the crazy groove swirls
冗談じゃない見えるはず
No joke, you should see it
そのハイエンドの風景の隙間に
In the gaps of that high-end scenery
さぁどうだい、この暑さも
So how is it, this heat
すれ違いそうだった価値観も
And the values that almost passed each other by?
「悪くないかな」
“Not so bad, I guess”
目を開き、手を取り合ったら
If we open our eyes and take each other's hands
案外チープな言葉も
Unexpectedly cheap words
合言葉だって言い合える
Can also be said as a password
少しだけ前を向ける
I can look forward just a little
少年少女前を向く
Boys and girls, look forward
眩む炎天すら希望論だって
Even the dizzying heat is a theory of hope
「思い出し」
“Remembering”
「口に出す」
“Speaking out”
不可思議な出会いと別れを
The mysterious meetings and partings
ねぇねぇ、突飛な世界のこと
Hey, hey, about the wild world
さぁさぁ、笑い飛ばせたんだった
Now, now, we could just laugh it off
合図が終わる
The signal ends
少年少女前を向く
Boys and girls, look forward
眩む炎天すら希望論だって
Even the dizzying heat is a theory of hope
「掴み取れ」
“Seize it”
「掴み取れ」と
太陽が赤く燃え上がる
The sun burns bright red
さあさあ、これが最後（フィナーレ）だ
Now, now, this is the finale
さぁさぁ、その目を見開いて
Now, now, open those eyes wide
オーバーな空想戦線、
Beyond the fantasy front line,
感情性のメビウスの先へ
Beyond the Mobius of emotionality
holoXスペシャルメドレー
holoX Special Medley
今日ライブを見に来た貴様らー！
You lot who came to see the live today!
そこに跪け！
Kneel there!
停滞してるような現実は
A reality that seems stagnant
一刀両断叩き切れ
Cut it down with a single stroke
終わりなき輪廻に迷いし子等よ
O children lost in the endless cycle of rebirth
漆黒の翼で誘おう
Let us invite you with pitch-black wings
我ら　エデンの星を統べる者
We, the rulers of the Star of Eden
秘密結社holoX！
Secret Society holoX!
でござる！
De gozaru!
WAO!!
さあ、holoXスペシャルメドレー！
Now, the holoX Special Medley!
いくよー！
Here we go!
あっちゃっちゃ！びっくりしすぎで　できないじゃん
Uh-oh! I'm too surprised, I can't do it
間違って悩んだり　ぱんぱんじゃん
Making mistakes and worrying, it's packed
けど君に見つけてほしくて
But I wanted you to find me,
僕は君を目指したんだ
so I aimed for you
出会えたならハッピー
If we met, I'm happy
叫んじゃえ　泣いて泣いて愛して　ビビビッて
Shout it out! Cry, cry, love, and feel the spark
叫んじゃえ　ダメな僕とどうか手を取っておいて
Shout it out! Please take the hand of the useless me
もう君の心チクッとしちゃえ
Prick your heart already
先も見えない乱世
In these turbulent times with no future,
自分のみち通りゃんせ
pass along your own path
オーケー　生きてりゃきっと
Okay, if you're alive, it'll surely
なんとかなるさ
work out somehow
だいじょうぶ　だいじょうぶ
It's all right, it's all right
後ろ　前　方向なんて　お構いなし
Backward, forward, the direction doesn't matter
こんな迷宮入りの
Even in these maze-like
毎日も一歩
daily lives, one step
歩き出せたら　それが前になるのさ
If you can start walking, that becomes forward
乱気流　気分な朝でも
Even on mornings with turbulent feelings,
頭渋滞気味の夜でも
or nights when your head feels congested
風がいつも吹いてる
The wind is always blowing
心配しないで
Don't worry
一緒にファイトでござるね！
Let's fight together, de gozaru!
擦り減って濁ってアイラブ自分
Worn down and muddy, I love myself
いつだってそうやって篭って不干渉
Always like that, staying secluded and non-interfering
大きなキスをしてみるけど
I try to give a big kiss, but it hurts
乾いたカサブタ痛ってなるんだ
like a dry scab
我儘に選んではポイ捨てして
Choosing selfishly then throwing away,
理屈抜きで夢とか信じた
believing in dreams without logic
メトロ溶かしちゃう
Dissolving the metro,
マリオネットなんかじゃない
I'm not a marionette
期待だ！ほら　いい値もっと
Expectation! Look, value it more
つまんない遊び場のシンデレラ
Cinderella of a boring playground
叶えたい　消えてゆく
Want to come true, fading away
叶えたい 消えたい 歪んでいくんだ 僕と僕との境界線
I want it to come true, I want to disappear, it's becoming distorted, the boundary between me and myself
それも正解で どれも正解だ
That's also a correct answer, everything is a correct answer
叶えたい 消えたい 歪んでいくんだ 僕と僕との境界線
I want it to come true, I want to disappear, it's becoming distorted, the boundary between me and myself
君だけに教えてもいいか
Can I tell only you?
MAKE ME NASTY BUTTER HAPPY
君は君 いらぬ義理飽き
You are you, tired of unnecessary obligations
不毛な怒濤 焦らすプロット 乗るか及ぶかで はい
A fruitless surge, a teasing plot, whether to join or match, yes
UP AND DOWN
我が道を行くマイノリティ あざとくアイロニー
A minority going my own way, cunningly ironic
知らずに見せるピュアなハートの殺生な命
The ruthless life of a pure heart unknowingly shown
夢描いて 全て描いて 脱ぎな風に
Drawing dreams, drawing everything, in the wind that strips them off
君のすべて解き明かす
Revealing everything about you
心満たすよ その美的な知識を
Filling my heart with that aesthetic knowledge
注釈注釈的に生きてる体も素敵ね
A body living like a footnote is also lovely
あーさあ 我が道を行く 狂騒さ
Ah, now, going my own way, in a frenzy
さあ 黙れ 黙れ 黙れよ
Now, shut up, shut up, shut up
見えないね そんな強い言葉は
I can't see them, such strong words
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I want you to be a little quiet
ああ 私たちが一番
Ah, we are the best
今と未来 見ていたはずなのに
Now and the future, we were supposed to be looking at them
世界転覆 ヤヤヤヤー 見えそうかい
World overthrow, yayayaya, can you see it?
ドドッドドドッドッドッ エーエー
Dododdododdododdodod, ee-ee
この世のことわり ヨヨヨヨー
The principles of this world, yoyoyoyo
世界転覆 ササササー
World overthrow, sasasasa
あなたの街
Your town
世界転覆 ヤヤヤヤー
World overthrow, yayayaya
あなたの街にも ヨヨヨヨー
In your town too, yoyoyoyo
逆転世界 アレアレアー
Inverted world, are-are-a
約束の地まで バッテン
To the promised land, batten
死んだらミクロの愛を上げましょう
When we die, let's give micro-love
我らの絆は染み渡っている
Our bonds are soaking in
ホロックス鍋完成
holoX hotpot is complete
笑顔で囲めば心が一つとなる
Surrounding it with smiles, our hearts become one
我らこそが不朽の仲間です
We are indeed eternal comrades
SHAKE NABE Happy Lucky Solidarity
まっすぐのスマイルを届けて
Deliver a straight smile
この味を捧げたいんだおー
I want to dedicate this taste, oh
SHAKE NABE わちゃわちゃ ごちゃまぜで
SHAKE NABE wacha-wacha, all mixed up
有象無象に みんなでジョインジョイン
Joining in with the masses all together
あちあちのバイブスで埋めた
Filled with piping hot vibes
世界征服 不可避じゃない
World conquest is not a dream
せーので決めポーズ
Pose on the count of three
LALAPATA PALALAPATA
さすがは5人の元 固く組んで 声を高らかに
As expected, under the five of us, firmly arm in arm, raise your voices
LALAPATA LALALAPATA
電脳の海を越えるため
To cross the cyber sea
つまり冒険 不屈でいたい
In short, an adventure, I want to be invincible
素敵な迷宮
Lovely labyrinth
SUPER FUTURE PARTY LABYRINTH
心を解き放て
Release your heart
ほらどうぞ どうぞ 身を任せて
Look, please, please, surrender yourself
もう逃げられない
You can't escape anymore
ほら 闇に染まれば
Look, if you're stained in darkness
世界を塗り替えろ
Repaint the world
望めばくれてやろう すべて
If you wish, I'll give it to you, everything
常識 破り捨てろ
Throw away common sense
くるくる狂い倒せ 火をつけろ
Go madly wild, set it on fire
LAPPAPA RAPPA
すべてを食らいつくせ
Devour everything
LAPPAPA RAPPA
秘密を教えてやろう
I'll tell you a secret
暁光クロニクル
作詞・作曲・編曲：Luna
Gyoko Chronicle
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Luna
右も左も まだ僕ら分からずに
We didn't know left from right yet...
じゃあゴールだけ 決めてしまえって
So we just decided to set a goal.
姿形も色も違うけど
Though our shapes and colors are different...
同じ歩幅で 隣を歩ける
We can walk side-by-side with the same stride.
今日はどう過ごそうメンバー
How shall we spend today, members?
妄想でさえ 語り合おうよ 明日も
Let's talk about even our wildest dreams tomorrow too.
天気予報で気分が変わっても
Even if our moods change with the weather forecast...
雨のち晴れなら 一休みしてから
If it clears up after the rain, we'll take a short break...
扉を開けよう
And then open the door!
ねえ僕らどうしたって同じ 場所できっと出会う
Hey, no matter what, we'll surely meet in the same place.
上手く行かない日々も 愛しく思えたんだ
I've come to love even the days when things don't go well.
どんな下らない作戦だって 顔を合わせながら
No matter how silly the strategy, while looking at each other's faces...
真剣に向き合ってさ
We face it seriously.
誰よりも信じてた 必死に生きてきたんだ
We believed more than anyone, we've lived life to the fullest!
いつだって笑えるように
So we can always smile.
前も後ろも まだ僕ら分からずに
We didn't know front from back yet...
ただゴールだけ 目印にして
So we just used the goal as a landmark...
旗を掲げた
And raised our flag.
今日はどう過ごそうメンバー
How shall we spend today, members?
煩悩でさえ 預け合おうよ この先に
Let's share even our worldly desires in the future.
何が待ってたとしても変わらない
No matter what's waiting for us, nothing will change.
一つずつ積み上げた この欠片を
Each of these pieces we've stacked up...
後悔しないだろう
We won't regret them.
ねえ僕らどうしたって同じ 想いをきっと描く
Hey, no matter what, we'll surely paint the same feelings.
どこか足りないピースも それで良かったんだ
Even missing pieces were okay.
どんな下らない作戦だって 顔を合わせながら
No matter how silly the strategy, while looking at each other's faces...
真剣に向き合ってさ
We face it seriously.
誰よりも願っていた
We wished for it more than anyone.
日が暮れては帰ろうねと
“Let's go home when the sun sets,” we said.
当たり前のこんな日々が
Days like these, which we take for granted...
どんな輝く宝石よりも
Are more than any sparkling jewel.
大事だった
They were important.
互いにふざけ合った日だって 抱き締め合った日だって
Days we fooled around, days we hugged each other...
傷つけ合った日さえも 全部全部が
Even the days we hurt each other, every single thing...
鮮やかに浮かんでいくよ いつかの遠い
Will surface vividly, from some distant...
遠い空へと
Distant sky.
ねえ僕らどうしたって同じ場所できっと出会う
Hey, no matter what, we'll surely meet in the same place.
どうしたってここが 居場所だって分かる
No matter what, I know this is where I belong.
混ざり合った声も 心地良かったんだ
Even the mingling voices felt comfortable.
どんな下らない作戦だって 顔を合わせながら
No matter how silly the strategy, while looking at each other's faces...
真剣に向き合ってさ
We face it seriously.
誰よりも信じてた 必死に生きてきたんだ
We believed more than anyone, we've lived life to the fullest!
いつだって笑えるように
So we can always smile.
明日も笑えるように
So we can smile tomorrow too.
ホロックスの皆殿へ、いつもホロックスを...
To all the holoX fans, for always...
応援していただき、本当にありがとうございます。
supporting holoX, thank you so much.
よく３年前、緊張していた我々を
Three years ago, when you welcomed us warmly...
あたたかく迎えていただいた時から今日まで
even though we were so nervous, up until today...
皆殿からたくさんの勇気とエネルギーをいただいてきました。
we've received so much courage and energy from all of you.
それでは皆様に少しでも元気を
So, to everyone, even a little bit of energy...
お届けできたでしょうか。
...did we manage to deliver it to you?
少しでも皆殿が
Even if just a little, if everyone...
元気になっていてくれてたら
...has become more energetic...
とっても嬉しいです。
...I am very happy.
今日5人でホロックス
Today, the five of us...
周年記念ライブは最後だけれど
...this anniversary live is the last one, but...
ちゃんとやり遂げられて
...being able to finish it properly...
本当によかったです。
...was really good.
皆さん、声が戻るまで
Everyone, until my voice returned...
待っていてくださり
...for waiting for me...
本当にありがとうございました。
...thank you very much.
3周年をこの5人と
Being able to welcome the 3rd anniversary with these five...
ホロクサーの皆様と一緒に
...and with all the HoloXers...
迎えられて本当によかったです。
...it was really good.
そしてホロックスの皆へ。
And to the members of HoloX.
デビューから今日までずっと一緒にいてくれて
For always being with me from the debut until today...
頑張ってくれて
...and doing your best...
本当にありがとうございます。
...thank you so much.
今回、ござるのことで
This time, because of me...
ライブが延期になっちゃったときも
...even when the live was postponed...
快く承諾してくれて励ましてくれて
...for willingly accepting it and encouraging me...
ありがとう。感謝しかないです。
...thank you. I have nothing but gratitude.
ラプラスへ。
To La+.
何にびっくりしてんの？
What are you so surprised about?
一緒にバカやってたくさん笑わせてくれて
For doing stupid things together and making me laugh a lot...
本当にありがとう。
...thank you so much.
自覚があるかわかりませんが
I don't know if you realize it, but...
その明るさと優しさに
...your brightness and kindness...
とっても救われています。
...have really saved me.
ルイ姉へ。
To Lui-nee.
いつもたくさん話を聞いてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for always listening to me so much.
声が出ないときずっと連絡してくれて
For constantly keeping in touch when I couldn't speak...
ありがとう。
...thank you.
いつも自信がないござるを自信つけてくれて
For giving confidence to me who always lacks it...
本当にありがとう。
...thank you so much.
こよちゃんへ。
To Koyo-chan.
いつも頑張る元気をくれて本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for always giving me the energy to do my best.
いつも一生懸命な姿を見てエネルギーたくさんもらっています。
I get a lot of energy from seeing you always giving your all.
声が出なくて不安なときも声かけてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for reaching out to me even when I was anxious about my voice.
クロヱへ。
To Chloe.
ちょっとしたことも気にかけてくれて声をかけてくれて
For caring about even the little things and reaching out...
本当にありがとう。
...thank you so much.
さりげない優しさにたくさん救われました。
I was saved many times by your casual kindness.
本当は卒業すごく寂しいけれど、けれど...
Honestly, I'm really sad about the graduation, but...
寂しい...
It's lonely...
寂しいよ！
I'm lonely!
ばかやろう！
You idiot!
ずっとこれからのクロヱの未来を応援しています。
I will always support Chloe's future from now on.
困ったときは頼ってくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you relied on me when you're in trouble.
そして最後に、この5人がホロックスで
And finally, for these five being in holoX...
本当によかったです。
...it was really good.
皆のことがずっと大好きです。
I love everyone forever.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
風真いろはより。
From Kazama Iroha.
よく読めました。
You read that well.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
まずはホロックス3周年ありがとうございます。
First of all, thank you for holoX's 3rd anniversary.
諸々の都合で5人揃ってのライブは
Due to various circumstances, the live with all five of us...
最後になってしまうんですが...
...will be the last one, but...
飼育員の皆がたくさんの応援と愛を届けてくれたので
Because all the Shikuin delivered so much support and love...
最高のライブになったと思っています。
...I think it became the best live.
本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
賑やかでカオスで自由だけど
Lively, chaotic, and free, but...
ここぞというときに一致団結できる
...being able to unite when it counts...
ホロックスとの絆、思い出は大切に持って歩んでいきたいと思います。
...I want to move forward, holding the bonds and memories with holoX dear.
ホロックスのみんなへ
To all the HoloXers
まずは3年間だったり、途中からだったり
First of all, whether you've been with us for three years
or joined midway,
僕たち5人のことを応援してくれて
thank you so much for supporting the five of us.
本当にありがとう。
Really, thank you.
5期生のデビューから1年4ヶ月越しの
It was a debut as a newcomer after a long time,
久々の新人としてのデビューだったし
1 year and 4 months after the 5th generation's debut.
秘密結社が乗り込んできたっていう
It was such an unconventional form,
with a secret society invading,
異例な形だったので、受け入れてもらえるかなって
so I remember even now how nervous I was,
wondering if we would be accepted.
すごくドキドキしていたのを今でも覚えています。
I still remember my heart pounding so much.
温かく迎え入れてくれたホロリスさんたち、
To the Hololive fans who welcomed us warmly,
ホロックスデビューをきっかけにホロクサーとして
and to everyone who started supporting us
as HoloXers since our debut,
応援を始めてくれたみんなにたくさんのパワーをもらって
I've received so much power from you all.
元気に5人揃って3年活動してくることができました。
Thanks to that, we've been able to complete
three years of activities together, all five of us.
3年間、思い返すと色々なことがあったホロックスで
Looking back on these three years,
a lot has happened in HoloX,
みんなもちょっと心配になることもあったかもしれません。
and there might have been times when everyone
was a little worried.
でも、こうして5人団結してくることができたのは
But, the reason we were able to unite like this as five
ホロクサーのみんなが5人のホロックスを愛してくれていたからです。
is because all of you HoloXers loved
the five-member HoloX.
ホロックスは、めちゃくちゃホロクサーに支えられてきたなって
I feel from the bottom of my heart that
HoloX has been immensely supported
心の底から思っています。
by all the HoloXers.
僕たち5人がいて、ホロクサーがいて、ホロックスです。
With the five of us and the HoloXers, we are HoloX.
5人で迎える周年は今回が最後になるけど
This will be the last anniversary
we celebrate as five,
クロたんが残してくれた絆の形は絶対になくならないから
but the bond that Chloe-tan left behind
will never disappear.
これからも変わらぬホロックスを応援してくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you continue to support HoloX
just as before.
末長くよろしくね。
Please keep supporting us for a long time.
ホロックスのみんなへ。
To the HoloX members.
いろはちゃん。
Iroha-chan.
忙しい中、焼きたてクッキーいつも美味しいの持ってきてくれたり
Despite being busy, you always brought us
delicious, freshly baked cookies.
音楽関係のこと、こよりは分からないこと多いので
Since there's a lot about music that I don't know,
お勧めとか教えてくれたり、本当にありがとう。
thank you so much for giving me recommendations
and teaching me.
今、もうちょっとまだ心的に大変な時期だと思うけど
I think it's still a mentally difficult time
for you right now,
こより的には、もう全然問題なく話せてるから
but for my part, I'm able to talk with you just fine.
申し訳ないとかそういうの感じないで
So please don't feel sorry or anything like that,
気軽にこれからも話してね。
and feel free to talk to me from now on, too.
いろは：ありがとう。
Iroha: Thank you.
クロたん。
Chloe-tan.
伝えたいことはコラボとかでもう伝えている気がします。
I feel like I've already told you what I wanted
to say in our collabs.
クロエ：そうだね。
Chloe: That's true.
本音。まぁ別々の道を歩いていくことになるけど
To be honest... well, we'll be walking different paths,
友達でホロックスなのはこれからも変わらん！
but being friends and part of HoloX
will never change!
クロエ：うん！
Chloe: Yeah!
また遊ぼうな。
Let's hang out again.
クロエ：うん！
Chloe: Yeah!
今年、どこに旅行に行くか決めような。
Let's decide where we're going on a trip this year.
クロエ：決めよう！
Chloe: Let's do it!
いいよ。
Alright.
ルイ姉。
Lui-nee.
歌見た良かったよとか話してくれたり
You'd tell me my cover song was good,
こういう曲が合うよね、みたいな話を色々教えてくれたりとか
and give me advice on what kind of songs
would suit me.
いつも本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for everything.
さりげなくこよりのオリ曲のダンスをよく練習してくれていて
You've been quietly practicing the dances
for my original songs,
ルイ：最高なんですよ。
Lui: They're the best.
ドキドキで、ワオとかエゴイストとか、さっきもコーリネウムとか
it's exciting, you suddenly start dancing to songs
like 'WAO!', 'Egoist',
もうその...急に踊ってくれているのが
or just now, 'Corineum'...
実はこよりは嬉しくて好きです。
Actually, that makes me really happy and I love it.
ルイ：最高なんですよ。
Lui: They're the best.
これからも楽しみにしてます。ありがとう。
I'm looking forward to more. Thank you.
ルイ：ありがとう。
Lui: Thank you.
ラプちゃん。
Lap-chan.
最初はネタかなって思ってたけど
At first, I thought it was just a joke,
最近は本気なんだなって感じられるくらいこよりを好きでいてくれて
but lately I've been feeling that
you truly like me.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ラプラス：大好きです！
La+: I love you!
こよりは自己肯定感が低い方なので
Since I tend to have low self-esteem,
ラプちゃんのおかげで肯定感が高まって、実はめちゃくちゃ助かっています。
thanks to you, Lap-chan, my self-esteem has increased,
and it's actually been a huge help.
結婚はできないけど、これからもよろしくね。
We can't get married, but let's keep it going.
ラプラス：聞こえなかった、聞こえなかった。
La+: I didn't hear that, I didn't hear that.
ホロックスがこの5人で本当に良かった。
I'm truly glad HoloX was these five people.
未熟なところもたくさんあるこよりだけど
I still have many immature points,
これからも仲良くしてやってください。よろしくね。
but please continue to be friends with me.
Looking forward to it.
大好きだぞ！
I love you guys!
全員：大好き！
Everyone: We love you!
そして、こより。あ、申し訳ないですけどPSを。
And, for me... oh, sorry, but I have a P.S.
PSがありまして。今日みんなとリハ中とかに話していて
There's a P.S. While talking with everyone
during rehearsals today,
新しい夢ができました。
I found a new dream.
やっぱりこよりはホロックスライブがしたい！
After all, I want to do a HoloX live!
会場でしたいです！
I want to do it at a venue!
あの時は、クロたんを引きずり出します！
When that time comes, I'll drag Chloe-tan out!
クロエ：え！？
Chloe: Eh!?
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
震えろ。めちゃくちゃチャンスあります。
Prepare yourself. There's a huge chance.
え、何、何！？絶対に引きずり出すぞ！
Eh, what, what!? I'll definitely drag you out!
大人頑張るから！その時はカセ外してさ。
The adults will work hard! At that time,
we'll take off the shackles.
歌歌おうね。
And sing together.
夢ができた！ありがとうございます。
I have a dream! Thank you.
出れたらいいですね、絶対に！
It would be great if we could, definitely!
トントン...はい。
Knock knock... yes.
では。
Well then.
まずはホロクサーのみんなへ...
First, to all the holoXers...
えー、今日私たちのためにこの配信を見てくださり、
Um, thank you so much for watching this stream
本当にありがとうございます。
for us today.
ホロクサーのみんながいたから、私たちは
Because of all of you holoXers, we were able
こうやって3周年を迎えることができました。
to celebrate our 3rd anniversary like this.
3年の間、ホロックスでも、個人個人の活動でも、
During these three years, in holoX and in
いろいろなことがありました。
our individual activities, many things happened.
1周年の時はまだ不安定で、
At the time of our 1st anniversary, we were
心配もかけ... かけましたね。
still unstable and caused... worry, didn't we?
私たち自身もこれからどう進むのか未来が霞んでいたとき、
When our own future was hazy and we weren't sure
道を照らしてくれたのはホロクサーのみんななんだと思います。
how to move forward, you holoXers lit the path.
ホロックスにとってホロクサーは、太陽的な存在だと思っています。
I think holoXers are like a sun to holoX.
これから沙花叉はホロライブでの活動は終了しちゃって、
Sakamata's activities in Hololive will end,
ホロックスは4人で活動していきますが...
and holoX will continue with four members, but...
ホロックスはこれからも5人、
holoX will forever be five members,
そしてプラスホロクサーで永久不滅だと思っております。
plus the holoXers, eternally and immortally.
手が震えてる。
My hands are shaking.
4年目の新たなステージに向かって頑張っていくので、
We'll do our best heading into our 4th year,
これからも見守ってくれると嬉しいです。
so please continue to watch over us.
これからもよろしく。
Thank you for your continued support.
そしてホロックスのみんな。
And to the members of holoX.
まずはラプ。
First, Lap.
自由奔放で勘違いされがちな総帥ですが...
You're a free-spirited Commander often misunderstood,
誰よりもホロックスを愛し、メンバーを愛しているのは
but we know better than anyone that you love
私たちホロックスに伝わってます。
holoX and its members the most.
ラプが総帥しかありえないなと思ってます。
I think nobody else but Lap could be Commander.
自信を持ってこれからも私たちを導いてください。
Please continue to lead us with confidence.
自信を持ってください。
Please have confidence.
あなたは総帥です。よろしくお願いします。
You are our Commander. I'm counting on you.
そして、こよ。
And, Koyo.
最初からこよはやる気満々で私たちを引っ張ってくれて、
Since the start, you've led us with motivation,
私もすごく心の支えにしてました。
and you've been a huge emotional support for me.
あ、今もです。
Ah, even now.
今もしてます。
I still do.
2人でデビュー直後、不安なことを語り
Do you remember walking together at night
夜道を歩いたの覚えてますか？
after debut, talking about our anxieties?
歩いた。歩いたね。
We did. We walked, didn't we?
その時の相談事とかあったと思うんですけど...
I think we had a lot to talk about back then...
今はみんなに愛される素敵なアイドル、そして配信者になってるから...
But now you're an amazing idol and streamer...
これからも先陣を切って、いろんな道を切り拓いてください。
So please continue leading and blazing trails.
いつでも頼ってね。
You can always lean on me.
いろは。
Iroha.
言いたいことなかなか言い出さない癖が、まだ抜けてなくて、
You still struggle to say what you want,
心配になりますけど...
which makes me worry sometimes, but...
今まで通り手を取り合って、
Let's keep holding hands like we have been,
たまに遠出をしながら...
taking occasional trips together...
お互いマイペースに活動を楽しんでいきましょう。
And let's enjoy ourselves at our own pace.
またかまぼこ食べに行こうね。
Let's go eat kamaboko again, okay?
食べる！食べる！食べよう！
I will! I will! Let's eat!
そして、クロヱ。
And, Chloe.
もうクロヱには言いたいことを個別に言ったので
I've already told you what I wanted privately,
わざわざという感じではありますが...
so it feels a bit redundant here, but...
また。またですね。
Again. Once more, then.
お泊りをしたこともあったし、
We've had sleepovers,
喧嘩もしたこともあったし...
and we've had fights...
いろいろあったけど、デビュー前から最初に仲良くなった
A lot happened, but I'm glad you were
メンバーがクロヱで良かったなって思います。
the first member I bonded with.
それはこれからも変わらないです。
That won't change.
これからのホロックスを楽しみながら見ててください。
Please enjoy watching holoX from now on.
絶対引き摺り出すから。
I'll definitely drag you back out.
やだ。怖いよ。
No way. That's scary.
クロヱの健康を願ってます。ゆっくり休め、クロヱ。
I wish for your health. Rest well, Chloe.
4年目も頼り甲斐のない、アホな女幹部ですけど、
I'll still be a clumsy, silly executive in
これからもよろしく。
our 4th year, but I look forward to it.
楽しんでいきましょう。いつもありがとう、ルイ。
Let's have fun. Thank you as always, Lui.
じゃあ、最後に総帥。
Well then, finally, Commander.
お願いします。
The floor is yours.
なんで最後なんだろう。
I wonder why I'm last.
総帥だからだよ。
Because you're the Commander!
ちょっと私は恥ずかしいので、
I'm a bit embarrassed, so
みんなの方を向いて読めません。
I can't look at everyone while I read this.
えっと、holoXの皆様、
Um, to the members of holoX...
いつも活動を応援してくれて、ありがとう。
...thank you for always supporting my activities.
活動している時、いつも一緒にいられたわけでは全くなかったですけど、
During our activities, it wasn't like we could always be together, but...
5人で集まった時の実家感というか、
...the sense of home when all five of us are together—
台本が全く進まないほど喋り続けるこの5人が大好き。
I love the five of us who keep talking so much that the script never progresses.
謝りたいこと、感謝したいこと、
There are things I want to apologize for, things I'm thankful for...
感謝されたいこと、本当にいっぱいあります。
...and things I want to be thanked for. There's so much.
え？ なんか...
Wait, what?
ルイ、本当に... 本当に吾輩たちは喋りすぎです。
Lui, seriously... we really talk way too much.
楽しい時間をいつもありがとう。
Thank you for the fun times, always.
はい、ありがとう。
Yes, thank you.
で、ルイからは人間界のいろんなことを教わりました。
And I've learned many things about the human world from you, Lui.
吾輩は元から大人ですが、もっと人間として大人になれた気がします。育ててくれてありがとう。
I was an adult to begin with, but I feel like I've become more of a mature human. Thanks for raising me.
親？
A parent?
ママじゃんこれ。
She's like a mom.
これからもよろしくね、ラプちゃん。
I look forward to our future together, Lapu-chan.
そしてこよりさん、最近本当に気持ち悪がられている気がして...
And Koyori-san, lately I feel like you've really been creeped out by me...
そんなことないよ！ え、待って待って、興奮してます。
That's not true! Wait, wait, I'm just excited.
ならよかった。
Glad to hear that.
こよりとは、とても正反対だと思います。
I think Koyori and I are complete opposites.
努力家で正直で真っ直ぐなこより。
Koyori is hardworking, honest, and straightforward.
頑張ること、正直になること、正面突破が大嫌いな吾輩。
And I hate working hard, being honest, and taking things head-on.
だからこそ、こよりのことを本気で尊敬しています。
That's exactly why I truly respect you, Koyori.
早く結婚しようね。
Let's get married soon, okay?
おぉい、アンサー言われてたんだ。
Whoa, that was the answer!
いろは。バカガキ。
Iroha. You stupid brat.
いろはも吾輩にはないもの、たくさん持っています。
Iroha, you also have many things that I don't.
こいつは本当に一生懸命で、頑張ることをやめません。
She's truly dedicated and never stops working hard.
でもたまに空回りしているようで、いろは、吾輩が助けてやるから、ってなっちまいます。
But sometimes it seems like you're spinning your wheels, and it makes me want to step in and help.
悪友、ライバル、家族、全部まとめた塊みたいな、いろはです。
You're like a combination of a bad influence, a rival, and family, Iroha.
これからもたくさん殴らせてください。
Please let me punch you a lot from now on, too.
いいよ、殴り返すけどね。
Sure, but I'll punch you back.
無理です。ひどいよ。
No way. That's mean.
そして、クロヱ。お勤めご苦労様でした。
And, Chloe. Good work with your duties.
謝りなさいよ！ 消えるでしょ！
Apologize! I'm gonna disappear!
クロヱはさ、この前LINEで「ラプラスって本当に優しいよね」って送ってきたけど、
Chloe, you sent me a LINE the other day saying "Laplus is really kind," but...
あれはどういうことなんでしょうか？
...what was that about?
本当にやめて！ 本当に本当にやめて、それは！
Stop it! Seriously, seriously stop that!
吾輩はクロヱに優しくした覚えがなくて。
I don't recall being kind to Chloe.
じゃあもういいよ！ 忘れてくれよ、じゃあ！
Fine, then! Just forget it!
あとクロヱさんは吾輩の歌が好きすぎるんじゃないでしょうか？
Also, Chloe, don't you like my singing a bit too much?
いや、いいよね。
Well, it is good.
クロヱのチャンネルから吾輩との「歌ってみた」が2本も上がってるし。
There are already two "Cover Songs" with me on Chloe's channel.
吾輩とだけです。これ、カウントいいでしょうか？
It's only with me. Can I count this?
これは「好きだな」と思ってます。
I take this as you liking me.
最後に、本音が聞きたいです。たくさん聞きたいことがあるし、
Finally, I want to hear your true feelings. There's so much I want to ask...
たくさん言いたいこともあるし、本当はもっと一緒に歌いたかったし。
...and so much I want to say, and honestly, I wanted to sing together more.
クロヱもそうだよね。
Chloe, you feel the same, right?
クロヱ、辞めるなんて全然思ってなくて、今までずっと自分勝手にやってて、
Chloe, I never thought you'd leave, and I've just been acting selfishly until now...
改めて、holoXって大切だなって思いました。
...but it made me realize once again how important holoX is.
今更めちゃくちゃやりたいこととか思い浮かんじゃって、吾輩めっちゃバカじゃん。
Now, all these things I want to do are coming to mind—I'm such an idiot.
でも、「クロヱ辞めないで」とか、めっちゃ我儘なバカじゃん。
But saying "Chloe, don't leave" is just being a selfish idiot.
だからせめて、ただのめっちゃバカになるために、クロヱが活動を辞めるの、我慢することにしました。
So, at the very least, just to be a regular idiot, I decided to hold back my feelings about you leaving.
でも全然、辞めるのとか嫌で、本当のこと言ってごめんなさい。
But I really don't want you to go, and I'm sorry for being honest.
でも、活動を辞めても別にクロヱ、バイバイなわけじゃないから。
But even if you stop your activities, it doesn't mean we're saying goodbye to Chloe forever.
自分を言い含めて、大人しくめっちゃ笑顔で、holoXで今まで一番の大物作って送り出すことに成功だよ。
I've convinced myself to be mature and send you off with a big smile, as the biggest star holoX has ever produced.
クロヱ、いってらっしゃい。ごめんね。ありがとう。
Chloe, have a safe trip. I'm sorry. Thank you.
大好き。またね。
I love you. See you again.
そして最後に、holoXerへ。
And finally, to the holoX-ers.
今までありがとう。これからもよろしく。
Thank you for everything so far. Please keep supporting us.
以上、holoX...
That's all, from holoX...
3年間ありがとうございました。
...thank you for these three years!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
じゃあ最後はエンディングです。
Now, it's time for the ending.
今日は来てくれてありがとう。
Thank you for coming today.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
どうぞ！
Go ahead!
えー！？これでいくのー！？
Wait, really?! We're going with this?!
エンディングだよ、エンディング。
It's the ending, the ending.
エンディングまで出すの？
Even the ending is coming out?
最後だよ、最後。
It's the last part, the last part.
どうぞ！
Go ahead!
何これー！？
What is this!?
Can you feel my soul
Baby, up & up now
Nothing bad happened.
MIRA
Deal with the devil
ハイドアンド・シーク
Hide and Seek
holoX Secret Silhouette
サマータイムレコード
Summer Time Record
大量GET！？holoXクレーン！
A huge catch?! holoX Crane!
ハッピー・ラッキー・Solidarity
Happy Lucky Solidarity
みんな！みんなみんなみんな！
Everyone! Everyone everyone everyone!
なーに？
What is it?
カメラ持ってきた。カメラ、ほら。
I brought a camera. See, a camera.
おー、カメラ？
Oh, a camera?
珍しいー。
That's rare.
写真撮るよ、写真。撮る撮る。
I'm taking a photo, a photo. I'll take one.
豪華、豪華。
Fancy, fancy.
え、みんなで？写真撮るの？
Wait, all of us? Taking a photo?
写真撮るよ！
I'm taking a photo!
おー！
Oh!
おいで、おいで。はいはい。
Come here, come here. Okay, okay.
じゃ、みんな最高の笑顔で。
Okay, everyone with your best smiles.
３、２、１...
3, 2, 1...
パシャ！
Flash!
イェーイ！
Yay!
祝・３周年！本当にありがとう！大好き！！
Happy 3rd Anniversary! Thank you so much! We love you!!
吾輩と YMD!!
Me and YMD!!
いつもサンキュー！大好きやで♡
Thanks as always! I love you all♡
祝！3周年！！これからもよろしくね♡♡♡
Congrats on 3 years!! Let's keep it up♡♡♡
本当にありがとう 大好き！！次のステージへいこう！！
Thank you so much, I love you!!
Let's head to the next stage!!
祝！3周年！おめでとう！これからもがんばるでござる！
今後もよろしくでござる！
Congrats! 3 years! Happy anniversary!
I'll keep doing my best! Please keep supporting me!
みてくれてありがとう！大好きだよ！4周年もよろしくね！
Thanks for watching! We love you!
Look forward to the 4th anniversary too!